

Lalit Kumar Soren

React Native Developer(1.8 YoE in FrontEnd Dev)

Enthusiastic React Native Developer with **1.8 year** of industry experience and expertise in **React Native** Developer. I'm eager to contribute and add value to your projects. Please contact me to find out how I might contribute and add value to your next project. Here are my contact details.

Ahmadabad, India

in linkedin.com/in/lalitkumarsoren

+91-7978850565

lalitsoren.vercel.app/

github.com/lalit58

WORK EXPERIENCE

React Native Developer

itservicesindia 🗷

05/2023 - Present Ahmadabad Its a product based start up with some out soucing project also Achievements/Tasks

- Project Contributions: Developed and maintained crossplatform mobile applications using React Native for My Squard project.
- Tech Stack and Tools: Utilized React Native, Redux, and React-Hoock to create responsive and performant mobile applications.
- Problem Solving: Resolved critical performance issues & Design complete project single handed in a React Native application, reducing load times by 30% through code optimization and debugging.
- Teamwork: Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including designers, QA testers and back-end developer, to ensure the timely delivery of high-quality React Native applications.

Software Engineer

industry Along with a lot of functionality.

2tab.com 🗷

04/2022 - 05/2023 Bhubaneswar It is a health tech product based startup, Which is providing API to Parma

Achievements/Tasks

- Software Development using MERN: Full-stack web
 development using MERN stack with expo and integrating
 Kafka, Elasticsearch for performance, scalability, real-time
 data streaming, advanced search and analytics on 2tab.com/.
- Web Scrapping using Node.js: Expertise in web scraping using Node.js and Cheerio library, for efficient data extraction and analysis.
- Data Modelling Using MongoDB: Skilled in designing and implementing MongoDB data models with advanced aggregation capabilities for data analysis and scalability.
- Fix Bugs used Ruby on Rails: Give support to existing webpage to fix some bugs and change the business requirement on live server.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Application (MCA)

Odisha University of Technology and Research, Bhubaneswar, Odisha (Formerly CET)

SKILLS



PROJECTS

My Squad (05/2023 - Present)

- AS a mobile application developer Replicate complete UI replicate from xd design in React native
- Call the api and manage and handle data with Props,React Hooks and Redux

Vechit (07/2023 - Present)

- Creating component and screen in React native
- Manage data and api calls

E-Commerce Mobile Application (01/2023 - Present)

- Develop a user-friendly e-commerce app for Android and iOS using React Native, with Node.js and MongoDB for backend. Efficient product search, purchase and tracking will save time and increase productivity. Node.js and MongoDB-powered admin dashboard provides analytics for optimized business operations.
- GitHub Link:- https://github.com/lalit58/e-comRN.

ACHIEVEMENTS

National Means-cum-merit Scholarship Scheme(NMMSS) (05/2010 - 05/2013)

It is National level Competitive exam, If someone clear it Ministry of Education, India Gives Scholarship.

LANGUAGES

English Full Professional Proficiency Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Odia

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Mentoring

Novel Reading

Stock Market

08/2019 - 04/2022

CGPA: 9.08